Raymond Selent

Data Analyst

Highly structured, gritty, curious Data Professional with strong analytical, visualization, and research skills. Bringing communication, teamwork, and customer service skills from 10 years in IT consultancy, as well as a bold, creative approach to problem solving honed from studies in theatre.

>~	rselent@ufl.edu
	954-990-3121
Ç	Fort Lauderdale, FL
<u>~~~</u>	rselent.github.io
ir	linkedin.com/in/rselent

github.com/rselent ()

EDUCATION & TRAINING

Data Science

Lambda School of Computer Science and Web Development

11/2019 - 08/2020 Remote

- 9-month Academy: Python, SQL, Linear Algebra, Statistics, Data Visualizations, Data Modeling
- 1400+ hours of coding experience
- CodeSignal GCA Score: 651

Theatre

University of Florida

08/2014 - 06/2018 Gainesville, FL

14 00/2010 Guinesviii

Additional Coursework: C, Python

RELATED EXPERIENCE

Dramaturg

UF School of Theatre + Dance

01/2018 - 05/2018

- Self-organized contextual research & analysis of Restoration comedy The Beaux' Stratagem
- Supported and empowered a team of 24+ cast & crew members, being both a controlled source of information and relieving cast & crew of research burdens
- Triaged questions and communicated answers, research findings, insights, and notes during daily production meetings & rehearsals

Virtual Chief Information OfficerConsultant

02/2006 - 07/2016

- Partnered with business leaders and took ownership of all processes, successes, & failures
- Interviewed owners & employees to understand IT challenges and identify root causes
- Recommended & executed forward-looking actions to strengthen connections between IT and business objectives
- Solved growing internal organizational blockers by self-teaching Python and developing custom CRM system, automating customer tracking tasks

SKILLS



DATA SCIENCE PROJECTS

Software Engineer — Schrödinger's Server (01/2021)

- Developed interactive command-line utility that reports whether a domain's web server is reachable or not
- Implemented checks to verify user input
- Built with Python within 3 days, using 1 library, and with no prior library knowledge / experience

Data Scientist / Engineer — Project Canopy (03/2020 - 05/2020)

- Led & advocated for 4-person Data team inside 14-member cross-functional Project team: established roadmaps, tracked KPIs with Project Lead, and reassessed milestones when needed
- Collaborated with Stakeholders and Frontend, Backend, and UX teams to create desired reporting dashboard & continually improve user experience within 8-week project timeline
- Architected & built custom ETL pipeline: identified 20 external APIs & data sources, extracted & cleaned data, designed database structure, and warehoused data in secure Amazon-hosted PostgreSQL database
- Exploited observed gaps in cross-sectional data to predict future events, fulfilling special product request

Machine Learning Engineer — P-H-A Assistant (01/2020)

- Built, evaluated, A/B tested, and debugged multiple prediction models within 2 days, using logistic regression, random forest, perceptron, CatBoost, and LightGBM algorithms
- Deployed best-performant prediction model to Heroku-hosted web app inside another 2 days (4 total) while self-teaching needed technologies like Flask, Plotly, and Heroku

Data Analyst — Airbnb Insights in NYC (11/2019)

- Sourced, cleaned, and analyzed 48,000-observation dataset of Airbnb listings in all 5 boroughs of New York City
- Created custom visualizations with Seaborn library, supporting and amplifying insights, analyses, and recommendations
- Discovered and investigated innocent-looking data points, uncovering potentially unlawful behaviour